VINÍCIUS BASSETO FÉLIX

Paraná, Brazil • vinicius1b7f@gmail.com

Analytical, detail-oriented professional with 6+ years of Data Science and Research and Development (R&D) experience leading and managing data science and data engineering teams, developing predictive models, machine learning algorithms, and data visualization tools to improve product development and interfacing between business and technical teams. Excellent leadership, team management, communication, organizational, and problem-solving skills. Fluent in English and Portuguese (native).

SKILLS

R | Jira Software/Desk | Confluence | Metabase | SQL | Power BI | Python | Agile Methodologies | Data Science | Statistical Analysis | Automation | Data Visualization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Gestão Agropecuária + Intergado - Brazil - Strategy Manager

06/2022 - Present

- Oversee the implementation of corporate strategy across all products, monitoring and mapping project progress, identifying risks, and liaising between technical and non-technical teams to align priorities and goals.
- Facilitate cross-functional collaboration within the R&D Department, gathering insights from different areas such as marketing, commercial, and customer success to generate creative solutions.
- Work closely with C-level executives to analyze and enhance product development strategy while assisting product managers and owners with introducing and prioritizing new product features.
- Collaborate with product management, engineering, and commercial departments to understand the company's needs.
- Perform analysis and project management activities using R, Jira, Confluence, Metabase, SQL, Power BI, and Python.

Gestão Agropecuária – Brazil – Head of Research and Development

01/2021 - 06/2022

- Supervised and managed the R&D Department, including monitoring the performance of the Software Development, Data Science, and Data Engineering teams.
- Spearheaded the implementation of automation projects using robots (Jira Automation and Power Automate) and web scraping (Python/R) and Metabase to improve data monitoring and decision-making.
- Applied Agile methodologies and software development concepts in the execution of R&D projects to drive continuous process improvement.
- Managed the department's budget and expenses while analyzing and reporting on key performance indicators (KPIs) and project outcomes to the board of directors.
- Built project teams, developed project schedules, and set project goals to meet overall project needs.

Gestão Agropecuária – Brazil – Head of Data

09/2020 - 12/2020

• Hired, trained, developed, and managed the data science team, providing constructive feedback and guidance and establishing a data-driven culture to optimize results.

H0 Consultoria – Brazil – Data Scientist Consultant and Founder

09/2016 - 08/2020

- Provided data science consulting services to companies and academic researchers, performing 40+ data analysis
 and survey projects for companies and 300+ analytical projects for academic researchers over 4 years.
- Assisted with hiring and training data teams for clients.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Biostatistics – State University of Maringá – Brazil

2019

Bachelor of Science in Statistics – State University of Maringá – Brazil